NYSUT Field Services Department Files. 6174/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  October, 1980. Confidential memo from John O'Leary to Executive Committee re organizing plans for 1980-81, including Hicksville, Cornell administrative personnel, Cornell ILR adjunct faculty, Ithaca College faculty, request for U.S. Supreme Court review, potential NEA challenge to UUP, nurse organizing at Miserecordia Hospital in the Bronx, PEF organizing vs PS&T United, October 21; PEF status report from Ron Peretti, October 31; coordinator's report from Vinnie Grove (Utica) re negotiations at various locals, workshops, October 16; coordinator's report from Leon Lieberman (Albany) re NYEA activities, October 16; regional report from John DeGregorio (Suffolk) re NYEA activity, negotiations, October 20; report from John O'Leary re organizing at Arden Hill Hospital, NYC Municipal Hospital, survey being sent to NYEA locals to determine whether services had declined, to find opportunities for campaigns against NEA, October 8; report on UUP from Evelyn Wakshull (Hartman), October 20; Mid-Hudson report from Stan Kern re negotiations, organizing, October 21; report from Ron Uba (Western NY) re negotiations, political action, organizing, October 17; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re organizing, October 14; activity report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re membership projections, collective bargaining, organizing Catholic schools, conferences and workshops, October 15; coordinator's report from Robert J. Allen (North Country) re negotiations, NYEA activity, membership growth, workshops, arbitrations, court cases, and other legal action, October 16; coordinator's report from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford) re negotiations, political activity, NYEA activity, with attachments, October 17; program for Regional Conference on Student Discipline, re positive approaches; report from Tony Ficcio (NYC) re strike at LIU Brooklyn Center, potential strike at NYU, settlement at Lexington School for the Deaf, Cornell Adjunct Faculty, October 15; regional report from John DeGregorio (Suffolk) re negotiations, NYEA activity, questions from locals re agency shop rebates, October 20; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re negotiations, organizing, October 14; report from Ray Samson re negotiations, NYEA activity, school-related personnel organizing, October 15
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  October 22,1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's report; list of articles for discussion; associated materials including article reprints
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  September, 1980. Report from Ron Peretti re PEF, noting antagonistic relationship, with attachment, September 12; regional report from John DeGregorio (Suffolk) re negotiations, with attached newspaper clipping, September 12; coordinator's report from Ron Uba (Western NY) re Javits primary, negotiations, organizing, workshops, September 12; report from Tony Ficcio (NYC) re "soap opera" at Wagner College, possible strike vote at LIU-Brooklyn Center, Federation of Catholic Teachers, other pending negotiations, demand for recognition by Cornell adjuncts at ILR School, September 15; report from Robert J. Allen (North Country) re negotiations at Potsdam, Watertown, Plattsburgh areas, NYEA activity, arbitrations and other legal actions, September 9; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re negotiations, organizing, September 10; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re massive layoffs at Elmira City School District, legal review, organizing Ithaca College Faculty Association, filing for certification with NLRB, attached Southern Tier Regional Briefs newsletter, September 11; report from John O'Leary re organizing Visiting Nurse Services of Manhattan, Bronx, and Queens, Misericordia Hospital, municipal hospitals, September 10; reports on UUP by Evelyn Wakshull, September 15, and Nancy Angellotti, September 9; Mid-Hudson report from Stan Kern, September 12; recent activities report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re Javits (Senate) campaign (with attached separate memo), negotiations, denial of unemployment cases, organizing, September 10; report from Vinnie Grove re negotiations at eight districts, Javits campaign calls, September 11; report from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford) re negotiations, September 10; report from Leon Lieberman re Javits campaign, organizing, September 10
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  September 16, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's report; article reprints; Report on the 59th Representative Assembly of the National Education Association, July 1-6, 1980, prepared for officers and staff of the American Federation of Teachers by Peter Learman, director of field communications, AFT/AFL-CIO (highly negative); monthly report of the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  August, 1980. UUP report from Evelyn Hartman, August 11; report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re negotiations, unemployment compensation denials, August 12; report from Ron Uba (Western NY) re representation election at Niagara County Association for Retarded Citizens, leadership workshop, August 14; report from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford) re negotiations, details on some contract settlements, organizing, August 5; activity report from Ray Samson (Rochester) re 20 bargaining units at impasse, organizing at Hillside Children's Center, Wayne-Finger Lakes BOCES (School Support Personnel), Greece Support Service Employees Association, decrease in membership, August 7; Mid-Hudson report by Stan Kern re negotiations, NYEA activity, August 12; report from Vinnie Grove (Utica) re negotiations, membership projection for following year, August 13; PEF status report from Ron Peretti to John Kraemer, copied to Vito DeLeonardis, August 12; monthly report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re negotiations, organizing, turnover in local presidents, August 11; report by Leon Lieberman re organizing, August 11; reports from Robert J. Allen re negotiations in Potsdam, Plattsburgh, and Watertown areas, unemployment compensation problems, NYEA activity, arbitration and other legal actions; report by Tony Ficcio (NYC) re organizing, strike potentials, difficulty in negotiating at Cooper Union because of Yeshiva case, August 11; confidential memo from Ron Peretti re PEF, August 11; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re problems organizing Ithaca College faculty, decertification petition against NYEA at Elmira, organizing drive for non-exempt workers at Cornell, attached newsletter, Southern Tier Briefs, July 10
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  August 20, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's Report; memo to Political Action Committee members re Javits Senate campaign, August 7; list of congressional, Assembly, and state Senate endorsements by NYSUT Board of Directors, July 14; monthly report of the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  June, 1980. PEF updated from Ron Peretti, June 25; report by John O'Leary re organizing at Ithaca College, municipal hospitals, observation that private-sector employers resist unionization far more actively and ruthlessly than do public-sector employers, June 12; coordinator's report from Robert J. Allen (North Country) re negotiations, agreements, NYEA activity in Alexandria Bay, Beaver River, other locations, arbitrations and other legal actions, June 5; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re negotiations, projected membership decline, organizing in Hicksville and other locations, June 11; report from Ron Uba (Western NY) re organizing the Niagara County Association for Retarded Children, disaffiliation of Cleveland Hill Education Association from NYEA, affiliation with NYSUT, with attached correspondence, potential with United Teachers of Buffalo, attached newsletter, June 23; report from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford), re negotiations, organizing, June 18; report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re negotiations, organizing of Syracuse Lay Faculty Association, June 19; regional report from John DeGregorio (Suffolk), re difficulties organizing Southampton College because of Yeshiva decision, June 18; report from Leon Lieberman (Albany) re projected membership decline because of job cuts, July 17; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re current developments, organizing, June 17; Mid-Hudson report from Stan Kern re organizing, anticipated membership decline, June 20; report from Tony Ficcio (NYS) re projected membership increase, organizing at Cornell ILR School, potential at Parsons School of Design, problems at Pratt because of Yeshiva argument by management, negotiations at Lexington School for the Deaf, Nazareth Regional High School, Cooper Union, Brooklyn Center, FIT, Taylor Business Institute, June 13; report by Ray Samson (Rochester) re organizing at Wayne-Ginger Lakes BICES (school support personnel), Greece Support Service Employees Association, Hillside Children's Center, York, slow negotiations, June 19; UUP report from Evelyn Hartman, June 19
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  June 24, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's Report; list of articles for discussion; associated materials including article reprints, newspaper clippings; report to Executive Committee from Vito DeLeonardis re New York City Nurses Hospital collective bargaining campaign and election, June 5; monthly report of the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services; newsletter, Twilight Zone: An Occasional Report on Bizarre Activities of the National Education Association for AFT Staff and Leadership, June 1980
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  May, 1980. Confidential memos to Vito DeLeonardis from R. I. Allen re visits to Elmsford and Rochester offices, discussing operations, May 27; UUP report from Evelyn Hartman, noting membership drive for new hires, May 20; Mid-Hudson report from Stan Kern, re settlement of Kingston school-related personnel strike, organizing efforts hospitals, May 19; report from Chuck Rogers (Southern Tier) re good progress in bargaining, organizing drive at Cornell, competition with UAW, May 16; report from Robert J. Allen (North Country) re negotiations out of Watertown, Potsdam, and Plattsburgh offices, NYEA activity, layoffs in many districts, arbitrations and other legal activities, May 13; report from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford) re negotiations, need for more office staff, May 19; report from Vinnie Grove (Utica) re settlements, potential trouble spots (strikes), health care organizing at Mohawk Valley General Hospital, Rome Memorial Hospital, interaction with PEF, May 16; report from Tony Ficcio (NYC) re hospital campaign, LIU Brooklyn Center, negotiations at Federation of Catholic Teachers, Wagner College, Taylor Business Institute, Lexington School for the Deaf, FIT; May 15; report from John O'Leary re organizing at NYC municipal hospitals, problem in that there was no time to create internal organizing committees at hospitals, plans to write monthly organizing bulletin for all offices, set up file of employer literature to help anticipate responses, conduct training, May 6; report from Ron Uba (Western NY), re successful Pioneer School-Related Personnel Collective Bargaining election, organizing at Niagara County Association for Retarded Children, progress after marathon bargaining session at Alexander and Kadimah locals, indication of massive effort by NYEA against UUP, May 16; report by Ray Samson (Rochester) re negotiations, organizing at Hillside Children's Center, Strong Memorial Hospital, Greece and BOCES non-teaching employees, May 19; report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re settlement by Syracuse Teachers Association to include agency fee, improved dental plan, 25 remaining locals still not settled, efforts to convince local leaders that teacher organizing had reached saturation point, need to focus on health care industry, plans to organize Benjamin Rush Psychiatric Center Hospital, Catholic-school teachers, May 14; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re organizing, negotiations, May 9; report from Leon Lieberman re NYEA organizing activities, NYSUT organizing against NYEA locals, political action in helping elect union-endorsed school boards, successful negotiations, bad year for layoffs, May 15; confidential memo from Ron Peretti re PEF, relationship with executive director John Kraemer, May 20
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  May 22, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's Report; list of articles for discussion; associated materials including article reprints, newspaper clippings; monthly report of the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services; Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, Fourth Annual Delegate Assembly (New York Educators Association, NYEA); blank NYSUT Survey of School-Related Personnel
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  April, 1980. Request from John O'Leary to regional coordinators for reports on organizing activities by field representatives, April 1; forms for organizing reports, with cover memo; Western NY coordinator's report from Ron Uba re Pioneer School-Related Unit election, nurses organizing, NYEA activity, April 16; PEF status report from Ron Peretti to John Kraemer, copied to Vito DeLeonardis, Jim Conti, and others, April 23; regional report from John DeGregorio (Suffolk) re negotiations, no activity by NYEA, April 14; report on UUP by Evelyn Hartman, noting political infighting, predicting increased activity by NEA-affiliated SUNY Alliance, with attached letter, April 14; activity report from Ray Samson (Rochester) re organizing campaigns for Wayne-Finger Lakes BOCES Non-Teaching Staff, Greece Non-Teaching Employees, election results at Rochester, successful Teacher-to-Teacher conference, April 14; report from Tony Ficcio (NYC) re anticipated bargaining at seven locations, organizing status of Cornell ILR School campaign, municipal hospital nurses, April 11; report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re organizing clerks, custodians, secretaries, lay faculty at Syracuse Diocese, negotiations for Syracuse Teachers Association, workshops, April 15; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re bargaining, organizing campaign at Cornell for secretarial, technical, and extension staff, April 14; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re organizing teacher aides at Freeport, Bellmore-Merrick, Herricks non-teaching personnel, Catholic teachers, unsettled negotiations at BOCES, April 9; report from Leon Lieberman (Albany) re assistance with lettuce boycott with United Farmworkers, impasses in negotiations at various locals, some settlements, April 15; memo and flyer from Lieberman to all NYSUT affiliates re money management seminar; memo from Lieberman to all NYSUT affiliates re lettuce boycott; coordinator's report from Robert G. Klein re growth in membership, organizing, negotiations, workshops, April 14; report from Robert J. Allen re negotiations in Watertown, Potsdam, and Plattsburgh, NYEA activity, organizing, arbitrations and other legal actions, workshops, concerns with Ausable Valley contract, leadership, April 10; report from Stan Kern (Mid-Hudson) re organizing at St. Francis Hospital, negotiations at New Paltz, April 14; report from Vinnie Grove (Utica) re negotiations, BOCES problem, stress workshops, possible layoffs at various districts, organizing potential at Rome Memorial Hospital, April 15
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  April 17, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's Report; list of articles for discussion; associated materials including article reprints, newspaper clippings, re nursing salaries; monthly report of the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services; NYSUT Legal Services Plan brochure; anti-NYSUT letters from NYEA
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  February - March, 1980. Memo from R. I. Allen re visit to Nassau regional office, positive evaluation of staff meeting, operations, noting staff dissatisfaction with location and layout of office, anticipated substantial rent increase, potential relocation, February 15; memo from Robert J. Allen (North Country) re negotiations, organizing, NYEA activity, arbitrations and other legal actions, February 16; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re massive effort to organize elementary Catholic lay teachers in Nassau and Suffolk counties, prospects for new rental space, February 14; memo from John O'Leary re organizing NYC nurses, Catholic teachers on Long Island, February 25; report from Tony Ficcio (NYC) re impact of Yeshiva decision, anxiety created, doubts of success in organizing Cornell ILR adjuncts, increase in grievances, February 21; report from Ficcio re organizing, February 3; Mid-Hudson report from Stan Kern, re impasse at New Paltz, organizing at St. Francis Hospital in Poughkeepsie, Benedictine Hospital in Kingston, March 11; memo from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford), re negotiations, organizing, NYEA activities, successful conference, March 7; report on UUP from Evelyn Hartman, March 7; report by Ray Samson (Rochester) re organizing nurses at Strong Memorial Hospital, school-related personnel (non-teaching: secretaries, custodians, bus drivers), successful conferences, March 6; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re one remaining unsettled contract from 1979/80, rejection of contract at C.W. Post, organizing teacher aides at Freeport and Bellmore-Merrick, elementary Catholic school teachers, March 4; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re bargaining at Harpersville, Greenwood, Bainbridge-Guilford, organizing in Elmira, positive early contacts at Cornell University for non-exempt employees, attached Bear Facts newsletter and other campaign material, poster for conference, March 7; report from Ron Uba (Western NY) re successful negotiations workshop, good relationship with UUP staff liaison, March 10; report from Vinnie Grove (Utica) re negotiations by Westmoreland Teachers Association, Improper Practice charge against district for failing to bargain in good faith, excellent early settlement by New Hartford Teachers Association, potential problems in Herkimer, organizing Oneida County BOCES aides, EEOC complaint against NYS Teachers' Retirement System by retired teacher whose annuity was less than a similarly situated male, possible litigation, March 10; regional report from John DeGregorio (Suffolk) re smooth negotiations, membership increase, increase in arbitration load, very well attended workshops, March 5; report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re organizing, negotiations, workshops, problems in two locals, March 6; report from Leon Lieberman (Albany) re transfer of Whitehall from SEIU to NYSUT, dues calculation, March 10
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  March 12, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's Report; list of articles for discussion; associated materials including article reprints, newspaper clippings; monthly report of the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services; NYSUT Executive Committee minutes; report on Supreme Court's Yeshiva University decision, by John O'Leary
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  February 8, 1980. Agenda and minutes; Executive Director's Report; materials re negotiations workshop; article reprints
- Coordinator's Reports, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  January, 1980. Report from Ray Samson (Rochester) re organizing nurses at Strong Memorial Hospital, NYEA activity, attached correspondence with Rochester Teachers Association, February 4; report from Ron Uba (Western NY) re problems in organizing hospital nurses, February 7; report on UUP from Evelyn Hartman, re concerns over funding of SUNY, February 6; report by John DeGregorio (Suffolk) re runoff election at St. John's Hospital with 1199, competition with 1199 and Teamsters at Brunswick Hospital, negotiations, membership increase, successful workshops, January 30; report from Tony Ficcio (NYC) re LIU Faculty Federation grievances, organizing, February 1; report from Robert G. Klein (Elmsford) re negotiations, organizing at hospitals, collective bargaining election for Mt. Vernon Monitors & Aides, growth in membership, planned workshops, continuing arbitrations and other legal action, January 31; report from Robert J. Allen (North Country) re Potsdam, Plattsburgh, and Watertown negotiations, NYEA activity, organizing, arbitrations and other legal action, workshops, January 28; memo from Leon Lieberman (Albany) re settlements by Albany Public School Non-Instructional Employees Association, Hudson Falls Teachers Association, strike possibility by Mohonasen teachers, workshops, potential problems at several locals, membership growth, January 29; report from Frank Squillace (Syracuse) re organizing Cazenovia custodians, East Syracuse-Minoa secretaries, Syracuse Diocese Lay Faculty, negotiations, NYEA activity, workshops, problems at Onondaga Community College Federation and Onondaga-Madison BOCES Federation of Teachers, press conference with Al Shanker, January 30; report from Chuck Rodgers (Southern Tier) re settlements in Binghamton and Johnson City, other bargaining status reports, organizing, workshops, attached newspaper clippings, Southern Tier Briefs newsletter, January 28; report from Howard Edelman (Nassau) re "disaster" in negotiations at BOCES, organizing Port Washington aides, Baldwin aides, Hicksville, Plainview, Long Island Secretaries, Manhasset Non-Teaching Personnel, turf battles for Catholic teachers, need for new printer for overworked secretarial staff, January 17; Mid-Hudson report from Stan Kern, re successful representation election against NYEA in Saugerties, organizing technical employees at St. Francis Hospital, need for more organizing staff if other locations (Vassar College and Culinary Institute of America) are to be affiliated, February 5; report from Vinnie Grove (Utica) re rejection of contract by Westmoreland Board of Education, Improper Practice charge, organizing, NYEA activity, February 5
- Working Conditions: Class Load (Arbitrations), 1983-1984 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  Summaries of arbitrations and full text of cases
- Working Conditions: Class Load (Arbitrations), 1980-1982 (Box 57, Folder 22)
- Working Conditions: Class Load (Arbitrations), 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 23)
- Working Conditions: Class Size (Arbitrations), 1983-1985 (Box 58, Folder 1)
- Working Conditions: Class Size (Arbitrations), 1980-1982 (Box 58, Folder 2)
- Working Conditions: Class Size (Arbitrations), 1978-1979 (Box 58, Folder 3)
- Working Conditions: Class Size (Arbitrations), 1976-1977 (Box 58, Folder 4)
- Working Conditions: Length of School Day (Arbitrations), 1980-1985 (Box 58, Folder 5)
- Working Conditions: Length of School Day (Arbitrations), 1978-1979 (Box 58, Folder 6)
- Working Conditions: Non: Teaching Duties (Arbitrations), 1982-1985 (Box 58, Folder 7)
- Working Conditions: Non: Teaching Duties (Arbitrations), 1980-1981 (Box 58, Folder 8)
- Working Conditions: Non: Teaching Duties (Arbitrations), 1978-1979 (Box 59, Folder 1)
- Working Conditions: Non: Teaching Duties (Arbitrations), 1976-1977 (Box 59, Folder 2)
- Working Conditions: Vacancies (Arbitrations), 1980-1984 (Box 59, Folder 3)
- Working Conditions: Vacancies (Arbitrations), 1978-1979 (Box 59, Folder 4)
- UUP General, 1978-1979 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, expense statements, newsletters; PERB decisions; membership totals by campus
- UUP Higher Education Organizing (1 of 3), 1978 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  Flyers re organizing at SUNY Plattsburgh, Oneonta, Old Westbury, Purchase, Farmingdale, New Paltz, Canton; confidential memos
- UUP Higher Education Organizing (2 of 3), 1978 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  Memos, flyers, newspaper clippings